JASON G. MANGIN

1151 University Village Salt Lake City, UT 84108 Phone: (843) 437-5934 E-Mail: jasongmangin@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Experienced professional with diverse experience in leadership, management, consulting, and change management including 15 years of leadership and management experience in complex and high stress environments in the Naval Nuclear Power Program. Adept at handling confidential and sensitive information with discretion. Over 15 years of experience with Instructional System Development. Qualified as Nuclear Engineer, Engineering Officer of the Watch, and Engineering Duty Officer.

KEY QUALIFICATIONS

- Leadership
- Gap Analysis
- Organizational Development
- Team-building
- Project Management
- Proficient with Microsoft
 Office
- Coaching
- Mentoring
 - Communication

EXPERIENCE

Independent Consultant:

Learning and Development Consultant (April 2018 to present)

Assisted various clients (small to mid-size companies) in all aspects of Learning and Development including:

- Gap analysis followed by program development and implementation
- Learning content creation and delivery
- Learning Management System implementation, operation, and optimization
- Knowledge transfer, leadership development, and professional development programs
- Organizational development and change management
- Coaching and mentoring
- Communication between and at several levels including C-suite
- Extensive experience with several learning management systems including Saba, Cornerstone, and others and content authoring software including Lectora and Articulate.

Santee Cooper (South Carolina Public Service Authority):

Supervisor Learning and Development (August 2016 to March 2018)

Supervised the scheduling, content, and delivery of all required training for over 1700 personnel. Conducted comprehensive training needs assessments, training forecasts, and training effectiveness assessments across many different lines of business. Audited all training to ensure compliance with all regulatory requirements. Effectively managed a training budget in excess of one million dollars and reduced costs by 50% in the first three months. Conducted a comprehensive overhaul of existing Environmental, Safety, and Health training to ensure effectiveness and compliance with current standards. Implemented a learning organization methodology and established formal procedures and improvements to numerous internal processes. Coordinated with operational business units to implement performance-based training programs based on Instructional System Development methods. Conducted a comprehensive overhaul and upgrade to the existing learning management system. Directly supervised the operation of the talent management system. Assisted

in the creation and execution of a comprehensive Diversity and Inclusion program to include the creation and submission of all necessary EEO and OFCCP reporting. Directly supervised a team of 8 direct reports in separate geographical areas that successfully met all training requirements using multiple delivery methods including internal and external instructor resources and on-line delivery in multiple disciplines including power plant operation and maintenance, public water services, power transmission operations and maintenance, and professional development.

United States Navy:

Submarine Officer (May 2008 to June 2016)

Extensive experience in various areas:

- Chemistry and Radiological Controls Assistant Department manager reporting directly to the Chief Executive responsible for the planning, operation, and requirements associated with maintenance, water chemistry, and radiological controls for a naval nuclear power plant. Additionally, managed the quality assurance program that routinely audited and assessed operations and records in all aspects of plant operations, training, and maintenance. Extensive experience with strategic planning and leadership, project planning and supervision, and quality assurance and auditing. Directly supervised 1 3 direct reports with indirectly reporting teams of 5 10.
- Shift Engineer Shift manager reporting directly to the Chief Executive responsible for the training, operation, and maintenance associated with a naval nuclear power plant on a rotating shift schedule. Experienced in various schedules including routine operations, complex maintenance periods, external audits and inspections, and significant change management periods. Conducted lectures, seminars, coaching, and mentoring with individuals, small groups, and large groups. Conducted various personnel administration and other duties including discipline, conflict resolution, and team development. Routinely adapted to schedule changes and other disruptions in a complex and high-pressure environment with cross-functional teams. Extensive experience with coaching and operational leadership and planning. Directly supervised 10 12 direct reports with indirectly reporting teams of 30 50. Additionally, supervised the training and qualification of 30 50 trainees.
- Division Officer Team leader responsible to the Department Manager for the operation, maintenance, training, and development of the team responsible for the maintenance and operation of a particular aspect of nuclear submarine operations. Specific experience includes: electrical, reactor controls, water chemistry, radiological controls, mechanical, weapons, and navigational/sonar equipment and operations. Directly supervised 1 2 direct reports with 5 10 indirect reports. Watch leader for a team of 11 direct reports responsible for the operation and maintenance of a naval nuclear power plant in various operational periods include routine, complex maintenance, and casualty response.

EDUCATION/QUALIFICATIONS

- B.S., Applied Mathematics, 3.91 GPA, Auburn University
- Nuclear Prototype Training Unit (Graduated 1 of 52)
- Naval Nuclear Power School (Graduated 2 of 81)